<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-basketball</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1893-04-01/ed-1/?sp=10&q=Basket+Ball+Game+Indoor+Sport&st=text&r=0.118,0.224,0.121,0.107,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NOW FOR A NEW GAME
Baticing Baae Ball inCaml In
stitute Gyuasuiuu.
A GAME ALL CAN PLAY.
a"er nianean r @Medsee-A Osmbinmttm
et haswases and feet natI-36e Ned eor
Deun-e.ss-A pset Reeuiring indsabnm
Tse laus ethe Game.
N INDOOR BPORT
which is new to this
city has bees iatre
duced by Mr. MauaI
A. Joyce, the athletic
instructor at the Car
roll Istitute. The
game has met with
great popularity is
other places where it
has been played, and
from the interest which
it hnt excited among
the members of the
Carroll Institute is bids fair to asset with the
Succes here that it bas in other cities. Almost
owery might basket bell is played in the gym
anshetts the institute, and the sport is not only
Smithy and invigerating, but exciting and full
ot interest.
Bushet ball wva Arst started about a year ago
ad ree that time it hes spread throughout
Se esuntry esecially in the gymnasiums of
he yong Men a Christian asociatioss. It is
paticularly adaptable to business men. as little
narmarx A. Joyce.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014635/1893-04-21/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+Sport</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>For a long1 time gymnasium instruc
tors were confronted by the necessity
for a game which could be played in
doors by old and young, male and fe
male. They wanted a game devoid of
lough features, yet one which should
be thoroughly scientific, and which
should atford plenty of opportunity for
good healthy exercise for the scholar
or business man, and training for the
athlete, feuch possibilities, says the
New York Sun. have been discovered in
the game of basket ball, which has be
come so popular in Fchool and club
fjjnnnasiums throughout thp country.
The (fame was first introduced by the
directors and pupils of the Y. M. C. A.
fill
tSOAI.3.
training school at Springfield, Macs.
Its advantages were t,oon perceived,
and the sport, spread to the gymnasiums
controlled by the Young Men's Chris
tian association, and was further in
troduced in scholastic institutions and
club gymnasiums. At the training school
Ihc g.iuic was developed, and a strong
team was drilled in the simple work
ings of it by James Naismlth, one o the
Springfield instructors, and an earnest
worker in i be Held of all-around sport
and recreation. In New York and
senator lVoui Delii ware to-servo for tha IJrooklyn.are sereral good teams, and
unexpired fl of his original term. H1 P'V "lt; a ir"IU w' l-l"ie-
This is the only case cf a father and The game can readily be played in al-
-sonLeing voted for by tho same icgis- ost the smallest gymnasium. As the
lature to fill the senatorial office. In sizeb of tht! exercising rooms vary, the
vpnate he served on tho committees sjauie purycu uy cuii iwiu ia suKuiy
on finance, judiciary, prh'atc land
rlaims, libiary and revision ofDaws. In
1SS1 ho was elecrcd president pro tem
nore of the senate. He was a.candi-
different. All th match games axe
played under regular rules, however,
-andth" peculiar disad vantage which a
"gym" may have for the visiting team, is
idate for president in ISSO and 1S54. In- remecieil so Xar as possible. Hie game
Wudinghigrest-rraiidfather, Gov. Has-, can be played out of doors on a large
Ptt. h i the fifth member of his fam- umuiibwcu an i .11 Syw
r 1 i. iin?iim. rrin r
piy wni) nave oecnpicu seats 111 11191
jUnitfldita,tes senate,
WHEELMEN'S PRIZE CUP.
r9 Be Competed Vov at tho Gr(At Kce
j The League of Ameiiean TVlieclmen
iJUavo been presented with a very hand
jsomo -trophy to baxrapcted for in their
;Sntcrna,tannal jaco meet, to bo held at
idiica'o next? Augnst, Il&nry Ij. Sal- j
fojistall, a. memUT of the Elizabeth A.
jfff Wheelmen, is the donor of the prize.
jit is a sterling bilvcr cup, gold lined,
itod stands twenty-eigBt inches high ou Jl". "v
The goals pictured in this col
umn arc iised, the upright one for the
field, on wliich it can be placed at any
point, and the other for Indoor play.
The latter is attached to the gallery or
the wall of the room. The string is
used to turn the goal so that tho ball
may readily be regained. These goals
are the improved article The first
goals, from which the game got its
name, were only peach baskets nailed
to tho wall or running tiack.
The game can be played by a number
of men at once. In a small jrvmnasium.
howover, flvo aside is the most con-!
In larger rooms nine
men can piay on a biae. Lnis is con
sidered the regular, number, and they
are placed a -hown in the accompany
ing illustration. Tho game itself is
strictly one of passing the ball fiom
man to man. It can neither be kicked
nor batted with the fist. The object is
to get the ball into the basket or goal.
A large person is useful, but one of the
best players it tho Twenty-third
htreet Y. Jf. C. A. gymnasium is
a little hap not much oTer
GOAL,</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86088296/1893-06-01/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+Sport+Indoor&st=text&r=0.141,0.009,0.694,0.613,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text><THE GAME OF BASKET BALL.
Interesting and Exciting Sport For Thos
Not Able to Exercise Kegularly.
The unnounceinent that at a woman's
educational institution not far from this
city tho students played a close and ex
citing game of "basket ball" wasperhaia
the first item which attracted public at
tention to a sport that is rapidly becom
ing very popular in this country among
those who have neither the physique nor
the taste for baseball or football. The
rules of the new sport are comparatively
simple, and the ease with which the
fundamental laws of the game can be
acquired in a few minutes' practice have
served to make it popular wherever it
has been introduced, while its freedom
from much of the roughness and intri
cacy of football has also tended to make
the devotees of basket ball enthusiastic
in their praise of its merits.
The name "basket ball" is derived from
the fact that scores are made not by car
rying the ball across the goal lines or
kicking it over the goal bar as in foot
ball, but by throwing the spheroid into I
a moderately small basket, which is hung
about 10 feet above the ground or floor.
To accomplish Buch a feat usually re
quires much practice, and as a rule tho
try at goals are far more numerous than
tho scores. Either hand or both hands
can be used in holding the ball, and it
must either he thrown or be batted with
tho open hand a punch with the fist or
arm, or a kick, constituting a foul.
The game differs from football also in
tho fact that no player is allowed to run
with the ball, but must stand where it is
caught, and a fair catch can be made
only with the hands. If the ball is held
for an unnecessarily long time, the um
pire takes possession of it and puts it
"ia play" by throwing it in the air, no
player being allowed to touch it in such
an event until it has struck the ground.
If a ball goes out of bounds, it is put in
play as in football, and no player is "off
sido," but every player has the right to
touch the ball anywhere or everywhere
in the game, provided the ball is in play.
No pushing, tripping, 6hoving or tac
kling is allowed, and every such offense
constitutes a foul, which gives one point
to the opposing nine. As a goal counts
but threo points and a foul one. there is
every incentive to avoid rough play. The
players advance the ball by tossing it to
some member of their own nine, and
there is the best opportunity for success
in personal skill combined with good
team play. The "forwards" and "cen
ters" usually toss the ball forward, but
when it gets dangerously near his own
goal, the goalkeeper often bats it with
tho open palm.
Ono advantago which basket ball has
over many other forms of popular sport
lies in tho fact that, while it allows 18
players to participate, it can be pursued
tho year round in tho open air during
tho warmer months and in the gymna
sium whilo cold weather prevails. Again,
basket ball can be played by persons
whose physique is not of tho most robust
type, although many athletes also have
found, in it a healthful form of exercise.
It has pypved of great value In furnish
ing exercise for business men, women
and children, as wpll as brawny students,
and from the general success it has al
ready attained wherever it has been in
troduced there is every probability that
basket ball will soon become a very popu
lar and widespread form of outdoor and
indoor sport. Boston Advertiser.
A Comfortable Ride After Working Hard.
Whilo strolling past the war depart
ment one evening I witnessed a little
scene that was amusing if not strictly
newsy. A small sized army of char
women and sweepers, who are employed
to cloan that large building, were start
ing homeward, having completed their
task for the day. It was raining at the
time, and several of the women, white
and colorod, were without umbrellas.
One of the colored women was just
about to cross the avenue when a mag
nificent team of horses drawing an ele
gant coupe dashed around the corfier
from Seventeenth street. The driver in
stantly recognized the colored woman as
one of his friends perhaps she was his
"steady company."/text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1894-11-25/ed-1/?sp=13&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Sport+Game+Indoor+Outdoor&st=text&r=0.091,0.617,0.149,0.132,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET BALL
JTHAMChGIVIXO GAlE 31ETWEEX
oPlioUORES AXD IRESllJIE
3 Iopular and Graceful Game bat
Has Foiinil Great Favor AnioiiK
Girls Some of the Rules nUll HeK
iilations Observed in PlajinK1 It
Basket ball is to tie womens col
lege what football is to the mens
The Bryn Mawr girls are particu
larly enthusiastic over this sport and
the Smith college students are in train
ing for a match game some day
Thanksgiving week
A picked nine from the sophomore
class will be pitted against a picked
nine from the freshmen class The
Smith college girl is immensely inter I
ested in basket ball which she also
calls cradle ball
1
I j
I
r
r
j
1DiUikct For IIKIOOM
Daslcct Vac Outdoor
L At Bryn Mar the students are
equally as devoted to this game in
deed their interebt in it is tremendous
and vies with 5 oclock teas and the
atricals in mitigating the ennui l of var
sity life The freshman and sopho
more classes are particularly alive to
this sport Miss Elsa Bowman is the
captain or the sophomores nine while
Miss Corlnne Putnam is the leader of
the freshman
WHY THE GAME IS POPULAR
The beauty of tne gameor one of I
I its beauties for it has manyis that II
it can be played by any number and
the more he merrier it is usually i
J
J voted The ideal number however is
nine on each side There is a goal I
keeper two backs to assist a center
a right and left center two forwards I
and a home man I e a woman in this
c1 TJ y
Tire accompanying diagram shows
the positions of the players
The end and aim of the game is to
toss a ball which is the size of a small
football into one of the two large bas
kets suspended at each end of the field
The winning side is the one that lands
the ball in the opponents basket The
basket is placed about ten feet high
When the game is played in the
gymnasium the basket Is bracketed to
tb side of the wall For outdoor use
it is supported at the same height by
au upright post The price of the bas
Jets or goals is 15 per pair for in 1
door use when supplied with a pipe
or post for outdoors the cost is some
what more The balls which are cov
ered with Jeather and about twenty
A four inches in circumference cost
about 3 each a rubbercoated ball
J can be purchased for 115 1
Basket ball can be played in a gym I
nasium in a large room or a small
b 1 HeW 01 a large field if in the latter I I
as many as thirty or fifty players may I
take part I
APPROPRIATED BY WOMEN I
The man who originated the game j
01 invented it or whatever the proper
word may be did not intend it merely
for amusement his idea was to pro i
vide a good allaround physical exer
cise and as such it cannot be im
P oyed upon combining as it does run
ning jumping bending pnd twisting
nearly every muscle and joint in the
body is brought into exercise
Mr James Naismith of Springfield i
Mass originated basket ball about</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1907-02-24/ed-1/?sp=30&q=College+Athletes+William+Lush+Basket+Base+Ball+Sport+Game+Basketball&r=0.185,0.121,0.422,0.195,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1915-12-26/ed-1/?sp=13&q=Basket-Ball+Basketball+Basket+Ball+Game+Sport&st=text&r=-0.212,-0.026,1.425,1.258,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Basket-ball Has Made
Great Progress In the
Past Twenty-five Years
Dy JACK HAAS.
The game of basketball originated
oer twenty-five ears ago. It was
Invented to satisfy the need of team
competition under indoor conditions In
which large numbers of relatively
untrained people could take part. The
majority of games that were being
piajed prior to basketball failed to
achieve any great Influence, nor did
they gain any wide popularity
All of our standard games are the
result of a gradual evolution and
have developed because they possess
ed those qualities that appeal strongly
to play or the fighting spirit. The
demands for special skill, speed and
strategy that is required in those who
indulge in baseball and football, are
great factors in the real pleasure and
interest that accompany the playing
or watching of these games, and are
in a large measure responsible for
their development and wide popular
ity. "Until the invention of basket-ball
there was no Indoor game that was
in any way comparable to baseball
and football In these respects. The
need for an Indoor game that could
be used by active, sturdy men was
keenly realized by the faculty of the
Y. M. C. A. Training School at Spring
field, Mass. Dr. James A. Naismlth.
now a member of the Collegiate Basket-ball
Committee, was an Instructor
at this school In 1S91 and undertook
to devise an Indoor game which
should satisfy these general specifica
tions. Basketball In Its first form was very
simple in Its plan and technique. It
was designed to be plajed by as
many as could occupy the playing
space, nine to fifty plaers on each
side.
It soon became apparent that too
many plavers In a gams hindered the
development of team work; so after
a time the number of players on a
team was reduced to nine. A little
later, about 1S94, the number of play
ers on the teams was determined by
the area of the floor on which the
game was played.
For the first year or two, at the
start of the game, the men were lined
up at the opposite ends of the field
and rushed for the ball when it was
tossed by the official Into the middle
of the playing space. This was modi
fled in 1S94 so that the ball was toss
ed up in the middle of the field and
had to be touched, by the center men,
to make the play legal.
In the meantime. In 1891-91, the
good qualities of the game were rec
ognized by Miss Berenson, the direc
tor of physical training at Smith Col
lege, and she Introduced It as a part
of the gymnasium work for girls. In
order to lessen the physical strain,
which was found to be too severe for
girls playing the men's rules, the
floor was divided Into three sections
by lines running across the Held at
right angles to the side lines. The
centers (the girls' teams under these
rules, which are essentially unchanged
today, haye two centers), the two
guards, and the two forwards, are re
stricted to their own sections of the
floor, so that the players in a given
section have an opportunity to get a
breathing spell when the ball Is in
any other part of the field. This de
vice not only made the game less
strenuous but also favored the de
velopment of team play.
It U doubtful If the history af coat-
jt-JVV A,-evi.-
petitlve games contains an example of
more rapid growth than that shown
by basket-ball during the first two
or three years of Its existence. Even
...im. nwwic pjnrau ji iM?cuail ill
the jears immediately following the
civil war was second to this. The
rapidity with which the knowledge of
basket-ball spread throughout the
world was due. first to the fact that
the game was so constituted that it
met in an adequate way the real need
for a vigorous Indoor game, and, sec
ond, the game was developed In an
institution which sent Us students, all
of whom had learned to pla) the
game, to all parts of the world.
The movement which has resulted In
the formal co-operation of the rules
committees representing the Young
Men's Christian Association, the Ama
teur Athletic Union, and the National
Collegiate Association, promises to be
a most valuable Influence In promot
ing the development of the game of
basket-ball along right lines and
should mark the beginning of a new
epoch in the history of the game as a
most desirable and useful indoor
sport.</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1913-11-30/ed-1/?sp=26&q=Basket-ball+Basket+Ball+Basketball+Code+Amended+Sport+Game+Intercollegiate</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET-BALL
Dr. Sharp e Takes Side of
Player at Intercollegiate
Meeting.
LEAVE OUT ROUGHNESS
Too Many Tecnnicsfities It Claim of
Coaches and Players New
Role Affects Centers.
New York, Nov. 29. Exception to the
trend of collegiate Icglsla ion was voiced
In no uncertain terms at the annual inter
pretation .neetlng of the Intercollegiate
basket-ball rules committee at the Hotel
Astor yesterday afternoon Dr. A. II.
Sharpe, coach of the Cornell football,
basket-ball, and baseball teams, took the
side cf the plajer and coach against the
rules committee, which, he said, was con
cerning itself more with ruling on tech
nicalities than on the practical issues of
the game.
The discussion arose when Dr. Joseph
E. Ray croft chairman of the rules com
mittee, and the presiding officer, called
for the consideration of Rule 11, which Is
designed to penalize blocking. The rule
had been amended over summer so that it
read: "A player is entitled to take any
position on the court but if in taking a
position he faces an opponent or makes
bodily contact with an opponent so as to
interfere with the latter's progress he
Is blocking."
Dr. Raycrott said that the change had
been made In the rule 'as part of the
general plan of the rulemakers to elim
inate all unnecessary roughness and com
pel the plajers to "play the ball and not
the man." By this rule, said Dr. Ray
croft all Illegal Interference with a play
er by his opponent resulting from the
close guarding of pla, would be deemed
a foul and penalized as such.
Dr. Sharpe carried his point because.
when the discussion had been concluded
and a vote taken on the Interpretation of
the rule Dr. It ay croft and Ralph Mor
gan, of the University of Pennsylvania,
secretary of the committee, agreed to
permit an editorial correction which sub
stituted an "and" for the "or" in the
rule in question, making it mean that
only by direct bodily contact can a player
block his opponent
The most important changes In the rules
forthe coming year have to do with the
"Jump" ball and the ball when It goes
out of bounds. In order to eliminate the
fouling that so frequently happened under
the old Jump rule, the players Jumping
for the ball now, either In the center or
on any part of the floor will have to
Jump with one hands behind the back.
The meeting ruled that b behind the
back was meant behind any part V the
back below the shoulder, with the hand
touchihg the back, rather than the strict
working of the section, which compelled
the player to have on hand behind the
back at the waistline.
The other rule regarding the Jump ball
was aimed to do away with a great many
of the "Jumps" along the sideline after
the ball has been out of bounds by giv
ing it to the opponent of the man last
touched by It The rules relating to
dribbling were also discussed, but no rul
ing was made.</text>
      </result>
      

          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1910-12-11/ed-1/?sp=53&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Popular+Sport+Game</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      

          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042242/1910-03-06/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Intuition+Asset+Game+Sport+Baskets&st=text&r=0.501,0.21,0.424,0.374,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Basket-ball Intuition—the art of
knowing just where to be and what
to do when you get there under cer
tain conditions during the progress1
of a game—is a quality which devotees
of the sport acquire only after several
years' participation. In football and
baseball events move along with sys
tematic regularity, but in this indoor
game the unexpected is happening
every minute. One instant the ball
may be in the possession of your op
ponents in the vicinity of their goal—
then every muscle is strained with
only defense in view—but a second
later one of your players may have
secured tbe sphere and at that instant
your whole theme is to get away from
your individual opponent in order to
open up an avenue through which tbe
ball may be passed to you without al
lowing an opportunity to block the
pass.
The ball may be located in a bunch
of wriggling players, each endeavoring,
without violating the rules, to get
it away from its possessor. A score of
conditions can prevail in just this In
stance, and they may be dispelled or
multiplied in far less time than it
takes to relate it. If in such a scrim
mage one of your men holds the ball
in his hands it is your duty to either
take the pass from him if he can dis
entangle himself or locate yourself
in the vicinity of the basket in order
that you may receive a pass from him
or from another of your players.
Perhaps in that instance you can
aid by blocking an opponent coming
down the floor to help perhaps you
can grab it from your comrade by a
rush past him perhaps you can do
more good by being ready to receive
a throw beneath the goal perhaps—
but what's the use.
Every detail, combined with dozens
of other details, goes to make up a
condition for which your movements
must be suited. A dozen games or
more and these requirements begin to
dawn upon the player who is a com
parative novice. Advice helps in
giving a theory to fellow out, but, as
my friend Prof. Lewis Gillesby at
Northwestern university once said:
"The only way to become successful
in all lines of the sport Is simply a
blamed hard grind three nights a
week in practice."
So in presenting the plays which are
illustrated in the diagram in this ar
ticle, I am branding them "Intuition
Plays." Take the one In the diagram
to the left. This illustrates a condi
tion during which your opponents are
endeavoring to make a free toss from
the foul line, after one of the players
of the team represented as aggressor
has violated tbe rules.
INTUITION IS AN ASSET IN BASKETBALL
No. 6 is an opponent trying for a
goal from fouul. He throws the ball
in the direction of his basket, op
ponents and aggressors being lined up
along the fouled lines. The center (No.
3) of tbe aggressors, being supposedly
the tallest man and best Jumper of his
quintet, gets the ball as It caroms off
the goal in case of a possible failure
by No.
In the meantime, the guard (No. 4)
and a forward (No. 2) have separated
themselves from the jam around the
basket, the former taking up a position
near the center of the floor while the
latter moves to a point just to the
right and a little up *:he floor.
Then the center heaves the ball to
No. 2, who in turn sails It toward his
own goal, where it Is met by No. 4 on
the run. Thence into the basket.</text>
      </result>
      

          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1908-12-06/ed-1/?sp=9&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+Sport+Strategy</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Basket Bail JBailStrategy Baili all allStrategy
i Strategy StrategyBy
i
By DR DRJMiES JAMES NAISMITH NAISMITHFather
Father of the Game GameCopyright GameICoprlght190S Gameicopyright
Copyright ICoprlght190S 190S bi Joseoh B IL Bowles1NEW Bowles Bowles1NEW
1 1NEW NEW ELEMENT S IN THE GAME
I was AI ar forded rded the honor of ofth ofth ofng
t
th game of basketball ba ketbal1 some somears somen somerar5 me mering
n ng
elements elementsicn
many new
ring ago
were remotest in my m mind mindno mindowr
y ten icn
owr nr into no the winter pastime PMtUnea
g field ld for effort If IfJtassarhusetts ItfrIends IfE Ifyllass
new ne
CD a
E Jtassarhusetts yllass yllassa rice friends t then had told toldien toldhe
hen he that a quarter of o a a century centuryatuetes centurati1etes centurye
atuetes would be planning planningand er erlt eft e
lt t manners of attack and on defense defenseconceiving defenseonceiV se seconceiving
conceiving onceiV ng schemes schemes of play lay to toHer toIder
Her and hoodwink opponents I Ihave It
d t have doubted but such suchcome events eventst eventscom
t come com to pass Year by year ear the theor
or for plays of new variety Is Isbring IslIng
bring stronger and the thee mortel more In Ine InIe
Ie e the better liked d by b coaches coachesI
I have pet et about aboutes to tell you youPS youhave
PS S fans and players alike alikee alll lr lrt
e f t center your our efforts how to tost tot tost
st t your plays to the best ad adage adedurlng ads
age during s the progress of plan plays playswhere plaRwhen
where to direct your our attack attackscience in ingame 10J1me
game where strategy and science scienceUidoing scienceJwiClln se sei
Uidoing i themselves themselvesthe thEmS lves lvesthe
the spectator tator who watches basketplay basket basketplay basketpIa
play pIa for the privilege of Indulging Indulgingcsasies Indulgingrstasles Indulgingrstasies
csasies over the wild movements movementsermoving movementsermoln movementsermoving
ermoving legs arms and Indoor Indoored
ed muscles the science n of f abth the theie th the e ee
ie e oustltutes itself in scoring sco scoarcuracy 1e leather leatherre abil abilarcuracy abllaNuracy
arcuracy In lodging the leather leatherre
re within the net nete
e Till 111 endeavor to demonstrate demonstrater
r t c science of this game gameability lies in inutility inabIJit
utility abIJit o M th tho guards forwards ana anaer
er to nork up to a highly em emit effipdnt e epclnt
it pcnt m the movementsede movements which whichIe
tde Ie the hl efforts at goals goalsese
ese irtKlfs lrt df les on Basketball Strat Strattherefore Stratthenfore Strattherefore
therefore will deal eal with the thea
a of the players about the floor floorsslng fioorsslng floorasing
sslng of the ball and the most mostre mostt7e mosttse
re manner of puzzling oppo oppoby oppoby oppuby
by a series of plays To start starttake starts
as s take the play which has has2e ha hae
2e e known as left forward to toforward toforwar toforward
forward In left forwards posl postof poslOf poslOf
Of course your our team must musta
a set of signals which are easily easilyed ea l1y l1yl
ed l They may be number signals signalsed
ed to the players by b the captain captainhe
he 11 e team or they the may ma be silentq silent silentjr
jr q In the rase tEl of number slg s1gtie slgtlie sl slthe
the same course Is I pursued as asused asused II IIUed
used In football For Instance Instancethe
the accompanying diagram Sup Supthat Supthat Supthat
that the series of numbers whlcn whlcnthe whlcnthe whichthe
the direction of the play Is the thed
d ottered by b your our captain Tour Touril
il I for the play pia left forward to toforward tof toforward
forward f in left forwards pos poswould poslwould post postwould
would be b 26 312 88 The cen cennamber cennumber cennumber
number being 3 the ball leaves leavesto leaveto
to go to the left forward whose whosen
n rat Is I while the last player to tove tovs
ve 1 the ball before the shot at the theIs
Is attempted Is the right forwardla forward
la o a2 a2ou 2
roJ ou may rea use us a movement of the thec th thc
c foot to Indicate n w certain play playnrtr pia playthe
nrtr 1 the th man who gives the 81 stdgnil e elsnal 81R1
lsnal R1 1 must give It unconcernedly unconcernedlyat
at It t nay 113 not be noted by b op oprts opt oprtt
rts rtt t and arc Dr made use u e of to advantage advantage1s
aftl aftlIs aftela
1s e placing of players imme immefly
fly 11 after the completion of the theKbJh thehl1 thevLh
KbJh proves especially effective effectiveIts
Its h accompanying diagram the theare theare theare
are idle Idl If the center of the therepresented tllorepresented therepresented
represented as the aggressor aggressortie o
tie t e jump on his opponent and ands
it t s the ball in the direction hull indiby Indlb hullby
by b the captains signal In this thishft thishe thisthe
the centef slaps the sphere to toeft toeft toe
e eft t Fide where the th left forward forwardes
jves es It and shoots It back to the theforward thefonard theforward
forward who ho In the mean meanhas meanhas meanhas
has taken up a position to the theff ther
ff r the basket from which he tries trlesn triesgoal
goal goaln 011
n 1 the truly tml scientific part of the theimation theinaUon theination
imation takes place The center centerJumping centerjumping
Jumping spurts for a position to togh
IgM gh side of the basket while the theoarl1 theorward
forward having handled the ball balla ballthe ballthe
a the goal tosser secured it iti it itI
i a bee line for a point directly directlysnt directl directlJnt
ant of the basket basketstudying basketstudying basketstudying
studying the accompanying dta dtayou dla1Cu dtayou
you can readily see what an ex exit
it t defense f this makes providing provldlnrlg
right rlg t forward falls In his hi effort effortii
ii the ball within the net You Toucovered YouQered YouCowered
covered every point toward which whichaU
HI uay bound as it caroms away awa
the goal It Is then up to your OU
to 0 leap into the air and again at atR atn
n R goal go L it is a noticeable fea feajjnat
jjnat that in this or any an other play for for2rertne forltter
2rertne ltter the plan Is for every ee play p1nrlose
lose his opponent and to do 110
mast aromplish a ompllsh his part partof of the thein
Ina inatlon J2A0rn Ion from a point T lnt otl other er than
in n which</text>
      </result>
      

      <result>
	<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-basketball/selected-articles</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GIRLS ILLUSTRATING PLAY AT
3IISSES HOFFMAN AND HENSEL
Of -High's basket-ball team, IllustraUng
methods of ploy whilo preparing for a
game.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1907-02-10/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Fouls+Basket+Ball+Basketball+Rules+Dribble</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TOO MANY fOijl Fo1ftjj l
IN BASKET BASKETPresent 1 1Present
Present Rules Too TooPrevent Stric StrjcPrevent E
Prevent Much M uch SpectacnX SpectacnXlar pectacu Nev
lar larPlaying larPlayingBY Playing PlayingBY 2 2l 2BY
l
BY ELWOOD S
BROWN tcz tczThere e eThere l lThQre18
There ThQre18 to A growing f irJ r rthe y ytho th ththo
tho middle weat for 4it hhr br a chs ch
the A A U b bII bsiktbah k ketball tbaN d ia ort or oriberal I
liberal l interpretation interJ1 tation of ofg Mim 7 Ths
irtg h j g hRs grown rown up U berus be beea lIst ot f fhat tht l lthnt t ttlmt
hat t the present pr 8ent rules are t t1O tmittlag uW Ui Uimlttfug jlse jlsemlttlng
mlttlng prHgUc pra prctlcslly tlctLU Uly no mom for forspectacular futS1 futS1spectacular fu fuspectnoulflr
spectacular plays pla s Fouls Fouksuch It ro cared I Isuch
such trivial offences ani an anhat fr frtlmt AXE AXEthat
that t many man games ar are areeating n Ilw and andosting tIIDt
eating because of thl thI8H thimunicated fn i j ht Z gin ginmunicated
municated with promine prominerom premium q isket ket j f ffrom a aIrom
from f rom Chicago west Mila iiiialmost na c ctlmost foj fojalmost
almost a unanimous unnnimo B desIre f a T Tthat
that t will eliminate th the i pr ierail1zr r ni OTt2SSa OTt2SSacalling t
c amn fouls Fouls minl 8J1tet K5 K5l r
calling are b bt ll1lnC inin inina 1000tbl
il a l IClVtWl CReror facIor lit In UlllJWOb almost OWIY every everyLooking iiIP J nI ir
Looking over the recent rpCt recentn nt J tnuj m
In i n and around Chicago li 4 i AHW AHWby Afd
thc t he Chicago Centnll Y M 1 l A
that t to per cent Of them tr tre trey
by b y free frt throws thr ws In a Ram am with withumble Jtb au n
lumbla h University 01 fouls Wre v re tee
the t he time consumed In walk Wftlklg g ft ftbringing f fj5 fj5asket
bnsket b to another trying t tringing thro1
r
bringing b the ball back to nter tt ter ternintites r i 111 z zminutes
minutes i cutting the actual jw1n ayintn u
down to 9 minutes In a i gmEo gmEothe
the t he Crescent Five team wl wllast w wist l va valast s
last l st week and the Jvansan snsas tity 11 tv j jclub A 1 1club
club c lub 67 fouls were called cutting cuttg9ir cuttg9irowi in inprevious Hr
down d owi eten more materially than thanrevious tL
previous p Instance This sort of ofourse ti ticourse thq UI UIcourse
course c has a stagnating effect f fenUre
etEd ujxi np
entire e game gme monopolizes monopolzes most f tth tthauses UJ tb tbcauses tl W Wcauses
causes c the players to relax ari arl 3 I Io i iginger
cs
ginger s and In i inn
general Generl makes the thean ui uin
an a n exhibition of clever free freerather tl thrw thrwtacular t
rather than good team work l lluther
luther tem a aacular
tacular t field Celd baskets basketsPlayers bukets an 11 43 3
Players in East to Blame Blame j9J P Pblame og ogOf
I Iblame
or course the plaer players U are Te In j p 1
blame for fot this because bacus th twy y foul p
fou
opponents opponent much more than is nee
Very Y ry little Utta objection objecton is made Iadt when Jec htr
are called caled for holding tripping A
tackle t running runnln the with the thf th trpping ball LH h hoffenses and anding 8 8offcnses
fnc</text>
      </result>
      
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-chicago-black-sox-scandal</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88078751/1919-10-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Inning+Runs+Cincinnati+Opened+SERIES+Four+Game+WORLD+First&r=-0.625,0.198,2.249,1.038,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Cincinnati Opened The Game By Making Four Runs In The
First Inning; Five Hits Were Made By the Red Slug
gers; One Half An Inning Was Sufficient For Williams
Who Retired In Favor Of James.
(BY THE ASSOCIATED PRESS TO THE BANNER)
COAUSKEY PAJtK, CHICAGO, J 11., Oct. 9 The sun
roke through .tho heavy clouds shortly before noon but an
extremely high wind'slming which gave promise of inter
fering with the fielding end of the contest. The bleachers
and pavilions were tilled long before tim for the game and
indications were for a record crowd. Clouds of dust were
raised by the wind swooping down upon the diamond.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-chicago-black-sox-scandal/selected-articles</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>I Comiskey Insists Sox
Put Forth Best Efforts
CHICAGO. Dec. l?r>. Rumors that
several members of the White Sox did
not put forth their best efforts ?lurir.J
the world's series were denied to-day
by President Charles Comiskey.
Comiskey, who said he had investi"
i gated the rumors since the report?
were first heard at the close of the
series, declared he has found no in?
dication of "double crossing" by any
of the players.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1920-09-30/ed-1/?sp=15&q=ATTELL+MAY+ABE+CITY&r=-0.193,0.071,0.763,0.352,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ABE ATTELL MAY
BE IN THIS CITY
Former Prlzofightor, Mentioned
in Basobatl Scandal, Said
to Havo Como Horo
Abe Attell, the former featherweight
champion of the world, and now one of
the central fljrurcs In the bnsebnll scan
dal expose, is reported to bo "come
where In rhtlndclphla" todny. Attell
lit Eeeking seclusion from his usual
haunts In Nftw York nud also confer
rlntc with his attorneys In view of pef
tilxtent rumors that ho 1h to bo brought
directly into tho expose by tho Chicago
grand Jury.
Attell hns been named freely by the
'hlte Sox who have confessed to tak
ing bribes to "throw" tho last world's
series as tho "go between" for the
gambling clique.
Just before he dropped from sight
Jn New York, Attell, when nsked about
the scandal and his connection with it,
M"Seo Arnold Itothstcln."
Rothatelu is a well-known and
wealthy New York gambler, who has
denied having had any connection with
the unsavory mess.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1920-09-24/ed-1/?sp=20&q=White+Sox&r=-0.145%2C0.043%2C1.004%2C0.463%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>With the gand jury adjourned until
next Tuesday, baseball magnates and
fan are watchtne the White Sox, for
their Tictory or defeat lu the series
with the league-icsatnp; inuians u
Cleveland may decide the future course
of the Investigation. If the White Sox
win today they will displace Cleveland
and lH thi Ipninip bv half a game
nan Johnson, president of the Amer- (A&u&l tfi
kan League, is reported to have received I numro Cle
rumors that gamblers are trying io
create an impression that the White
Eox do not daro win the league pen
nant. According to statements quot
ing Mr. Johnvm published by papers
here, the syndicate of gamblers which.
It has been charged, "bought" Inst
year's world series by paying 100.
OOO to five white Sox players, threatens
to expose the plot If the Chicago team
wins the race.
Mr. Johnson, It was announced to
day, will be recalled by the grand jury
next week to tell what he knows about
this alleged blackmail plot. Other wit
nesses Include President Heydler, of
the National League.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1921-03-17/ed-1/?sp=12&q=Owner+Sox+White+Terminates+Contracts</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1921-03-17/ed-1/?sp=12&q=Owner+Sox+White+Terminates+Contracts</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1921-07-20/ed-1/?sp=1&q=BRIBERS+SOX+BLACK+CROSSED</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>f SAYS BLACK SOX
OPKIDNAPPED'HN 1 ffl CROSSED BRIBERS
LITTLE ONES MOTHERLESS NOW
V 'Wi,.''.' H
mi'- '"w i -,v x v ,?'1 3 iH
HPhH
l.cilcer Photo fcerlc
Tho photograph shows four chil
dren of Mrs. Margaret LucalrctlicJi.
who was murdered In her homo this
morning in tho rear of 122 Spruce
street. Included In the group Is
an orphan girl whom Mrs. I.u
cairctluli was caring for. Tliey
aio, left to right: Annlo, six; Jo
fMlilne, nine; Kattlo Teimlui (or
phan); Victoria, two, and Mary.
The Insert shows Mrs. Sophie Pu
bis, who. It Is said, struck Mrs.
Lucaircllich oicr the head with
a milk bottle a moment before she
was slain
PEPPER'S CAR
Wife of Attorney Holds Boy in
Arms on Quick Trip to
Hospital
CHAUFFEUR IS EXONERATED
Louis Aldcn. four )curs old. of
I!r)ii Mnwr, was struck and seriously
hurt nt noon today by an automobile
owned by ficorge Wharton Pepper,
piomincnt Philadelphia attorney.
Mrs. Pepper wns riding in the car,
which was driven by Foster Heatty,
her chauffeur.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-chicago-black-sox-scandal/selected-articles</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1921-08-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Sox+White</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Jury Acquits White Sox After
2 hrs.; Lifts Them, on Shoulders
Seven Players, Zork and Zelcer Cleared in World
Series Conspiracy; Hundreds in Court Shout
Approval as Judge Declares Verdict is Just
CHICAGO, Aug 2 (By The Associated
Press).?The seven former Chicago
White Sox baseball players and two
others on trial for alleged conspiracy
to defraud the public through throw?
ing of the 1919 world series games with
Cincinnati to-night were found not
guilty by a jury.
The verdict was reached after2 hours
and 47 minutes of deliberation, but was
not returned until forty minutes later.
Judge Hugh M. Friend being out of
court when the decision was reached.
The defendants were Buck Weaver,
third baseman; Oscar Felson, out?
fielder; Charles l?dsberg, shortetop;
Arnold Gandil, first baseman; Claude
Williams and Eddie. Cicotte, pitchers;
Joe Jackson, outfielder?all former
White Sox players?and Carl Zork, of
St. Louis, and David Zelcer, of Des
Moines, Iowa.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1921-07-23/ed-1/?sp=10&q=Chicago+series+Series+BLACK+Black+Sox+SOX&r=-0.027%2C0.075%2C0.446%2C0.206%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BLACK SOX DECIDED
WHEN TO WIN OR NOT
That's What Bill Burns Soys, All of Which Makes
Interesting Reading But Has No Effect on Lack
of Attendance at Ball Parks
By KOIIKRT V. MAXWKMs
HporU Ijlltor Kviiilne 1'iiMlr l.rditrr
THEIIE lias boon n lot of tnlU recently nbont the trinl of the
.1 I 1 II I.-
X Chicago nllecung tue niieiiuiiiH'e m "ig u-huhc uu inn.
conversation anil cannot be used won ns nn exeue.
hokum nnl very niuoli bunk. Triio. the nttonilanco
Black Sox in
Tlii Is jut
In other words, it it
is falling off, lint not
Wmise there is n lack of interest in the sport. There in u shortage of dollar
bills these days and the fans have boon the iirst to realize it. That is the
reason, If niiy. nnd not the airing of the two-year-old scandal.
The trial in Chicago thus far has been Interesting ron ling and proved
whnt could be done to a well-ctnblMiod -port If it few participants decided
to wander off the straight and narrow. Kill Kiinis' testimony divulged the
information that two of the ball players first broached the subject to throw
the gnmes nnd scorned anxious to go through with it. Whether the defense
can break down this testimony tcm;iin to he seen.
It's a good thing for baseball and every other sport to have this scandal
aired. It will serve ns an example to other who are tottering on the brink
and null them back In time. Eight athletes have been publicly discredited,
-arc on trial and If found guilty will face a prison sentence. They have been
deprived of a means of livelihood, no longer can command fat salaries for six
montns' work nnd must start all over again under n cloud. The plot proved
to be n boomerang and the bos "didn't know it was loaded."
One of the amusing features of the tctlmony thus for has been the utter
disregard shown the Cincinnati club in th- series. According to Kill Hums,
the suspected ball pln.vors decided when to win and when to lose, not once
taking the Beds into consideration. Thej figured they were the best bnll club
and Cincinnati was the party of the seiond part, inserted for competition
purposes only. Therefore, n definition of false pride is the Cluclnnuti players
getting chesty over winning the 11)19 World Series.
There will be some interesting stuff pulled when the defense gets under
way. The players have smart law era and probably something Is concenlcd
In their sleeves. It is said that a couple of bombs will bo exploded before the
trial is over nnd several persons who have not been mentioned ns yet will stand
out in the glare of publicity. Just who they arc remains to be seen.
Yesterday there was some excitement when .lohn Scyes, secretary of the
Chicago Cubs, testified that he and CInrk Griffith held Fome of Abe Audi's
bets made In Cincinnati. There's nothing strange about that. In every big
athletic event prominent persons are picked as stakeholders because they arc
known to both parties. There were a hundred others like Griff.
nA.SED.LL icilf be a</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1921-07-22/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Series+Players+Burns+Idea+Plot&st=text&r=0.123,0.059,0.695,0.613,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Burns Calls
Series Plot
Players' Idea
??____
Testifies First Proposal
Came From Gcotte and
Gandil Court Rules
I N. Y. Talks Admissible
State Scores in
Conspiracy Charge
j Witness Admits Mistake
in Account of Meeting
After Opening Game
Special Disvateh to The Tribune
CHICAGO, July 21.--Judge Friend
this evening decided that conversations
held in New York between Cicotte,
Gandil, Bill Burns and Attell before the
1919 world series opened would be ad?
mitted in the records of the trial of
the indicted ball players and gamblers
l growing out of the "throwing" of the
games. Twice before the judge had
ruled that these conversations were not
admissible, but to-day, after the state
had insisted that it had proved the ex?
istence of a conspiracy by the testi?
mony of Bill Burns, it was decided to
admit the conversations. This is a de?
cided victory for the state.
Another important development was
the statement by Burns that it was not
the gamblers, but the ball players, who
conceived the plot of juggling the
world series. He testified that Cicotte
and Gandil had come to him in Now
jYork with a proposition to "throw" the
i series for $100,000. Burns also brought
in the names of Jean Dubu?, formerly
pitcher for the Detroit Americans, and
Fred Toney, now pitching for the
Giants. They had not previously been
mentioned, and their connection with
the affair was not made clear to-day.
Burns Admit?? Misstatemcnts
Give and take exchange of personal?
ities to-day enlivened the closing hours j
of the inquisition to which Burns, the
state's star witness in the baseball
trial, has been subjected since he fin?
ished his direct testimony yesterday.
The defence attorneys after having
examined him by batteries and in?
dividually, finally abandoned the at?
tack, unable to upset the principal por?
tions of his testimony. In the morning
session Burns admitted that he had
made misstatemcnts regarding certain
meeting? with the White Sox players
in the Sinton Hotel in Cincinnati.
Attorney Benedict J. Short, who
closed the examination for the defense,
questioned Burns concerning his trans?
fer from tho Minneapolis club of the
American Association, attempting to
show that his release had followed, an
attack on John Titus, of the Kansas
City club.
"I did have some trouble about that
affair," Burns admitted. "Titus was
hit by a pitched bal!. They tried to
make out that I had done it on pur?
pose."
"When Gandil refused to give you
your share of the bribe money did you
tell him you'd get even?" Attorney
Short inquired.
"Yes," admitted the witness.
"Do you think you're even now?"
"I wouldn't say, but I'm liable to be
before this thing is over."
After Attorney Short had concluded
his questioning, Assistant State's At?
torney Gorman took the witness for
redirect examination in an attempt to
bolster up the weak spots in his testi
I mony as uncovered by the attack of
the defenso attorneys.
i Johnson-Comiskey Feud Brought In
An attempt by the defense to show j
I that Burns's testimony was obtained i
for the state by Ban Johnson, head o?
the American League, in an effort to
wreck the White Sox team and settle?!
an old score with Charles A. Comiskey,
owner of the Sox, was one of tho sensa
tional developments of the cross-exam-
j ?nation. On this point Burns 'refused
to commit himself.
The interchange of comment be-
j tween attorneys became bitter as the
plan to impeach the evidence offered
by Burns was disclosed. Judge Friend
intervened several times to preserve
j order.
i Attorney Nash, who opened the
cross-examination when Burns re- i
I sumed the stand at the beginning of j
I the morning session, occupied him-
I self principally with questions re?a-
tive to the alleged meeting of Burns
with Chicago players in the Sinton
Hotel prior to the first game of the
series in Cincinnati.
Burns admitted that he had not
arrived in Cincinnati until 10 a. m.
the day of the first game and that he
had not reached the hotel until 11
o'clock.
"Isn't it a fact that these players
were out at the park practicing at the
time of your arrival at the hotel?"
inquired Mr. Nash. "Isn't it a fact
that most of them went over to the j
racetrack in Louisville after the
I practice and didn't return to the hotel
until that night?"
Repeats Version of Hotel Meeting
"I don't know about the practice," re-1
plied Burns. "But they were in that
room in the hotel. I saw the in there."
Mr. Nash read over tho list of the
(Continued on page eight)
Harding Firm
Arms Parley</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-czar-nicholas-ii</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92070477/1894-11-07/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Alexander+Czar+Nicholas</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-czar-nicholas-ii/selected-articles</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Amid the Incessant rlnging et church
bells, the court, the imperial family.
the visiting princes and foreign envoys,
assemble in the large halls of the
Xremlln palace and follow the sover
eign to the doors, where the proceesion
is formed. The imperial couple march
under a dias of gold cloth, richly deco
rated with the Imperial arms-the two
headed eagles-and finished with a
heavy bullion fringe and gold tassels.
This Ie held over their heads by court
chamberlains and generals of the army.
A raised and carpeted walk extends
from the doors of the palace through
the whole circuit that their majesties
have to travel. The large enclosure
within the walls of the Kremlin Is
black with the populace, and as soon
as he shows himself the tens of thou
sands of spectators and the brilliantly
uniformed soldiers shout a mighty wel
come to their ruler--a shout that
drowns the church bells and even the
cannon that are fired continually dur
ing the solemn,march.
THE PROCESSION STARTS.
First in' the procession are the court
chamberlains, who carry the imperial
mantle on two gold cloth cushions and
the Imperial regalia. The train of the
emptess is carried by five ladles In
waiting; she wears a white satin dress
covered with gorgeous hand embrold
ery In silver and gold thread and her
head is adorned with the regulation
"kokoshink," or diadem of velvet em
broldered in precious stones.
The caar-a young man of 2$-Is
dressed in the uniform of a Russian
general and has the golden chain of St.
Andrew about his neck.
As the imperial couple enters the ca
thedral by its southern door, they are
met by the metropolitans, the arch
bishops and bishops, with the rest of
the clergy who are to officiate at the
coronation, In all wellnigh 200 priests.
As the imperial regalia are brought in,
*a m b wbs
ow a im ohm
m~tbdwbrws h.7~··P
smp2 b·hGst b to A.
ofth. 3me,.h o
a,."" this rt t
ia o o..
ý sv.. mewi t f~ them
dm teIm k they
tsar. tahr apnowi to i
he shww. o the chwbital
w a"t r s Joe" whom
o the osthreiuI a ae
topa 3.owtm tO th StottirM
be amoeetual thrum.. a,. 1or
bem while the membre at
f1s f'am.l. the eemuttwIn eft
asetatives of the nobility, take tetir
places among them.. The throne plat
form is in the very middle of the eq
thedral, and rugs of the rarest kind,
mostly presents from eastern poten
tates. cover the path from the throne to
the altar. On both sides of this path ex
tend the two long rows of priests.
Representatives of the lower olesy 'of
the people-the merchants and the
peasants-are also present. These rep
resentatives are stationed on the broad
elevation running along the three sides
of the cathedral. The ascent toward
the wall is very gradual, forming a
perfect amphitheater. The foremost</text>
      </result>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-czar-nicholas-ii/selected-articles</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MOTHER AND WIFE OF THE CZAR OF RUSSIA "WHO WOULD DI
RECT HIS POLITICAL. DESTINY AND THE WOMAN WHO IS
STRIVING FOR HIS DOWNFALL.
Since the day he ascended the throne
there has been a continuous contest
between his wife ar.d his mother for
supremacy over the Czar. His mother,
the Dowager Empress, though brought
up at the most democratic court in
Europe that of Denmark— became
after her marriage to Alexander III as
Muscovite in thought and opinion as
the most extreme Russian Conserv
atives. A Protestant by birth and edu
cation, she became a devout adherent
of the orthodox Greek faith.
When her son. Nicholas II, then a
young man of "6, became Emperor, his
mother formed a resolve that she would
guide him in the footsteps of his
fathers and protect him from the mod
ernizing influences of the age. The
Dowager Empress has been the lead
ing spirit of the reactionists at the
Russian court. She has sought to make
her eon a ruler after her own heart, a
statesman of the Muscovite school, a
The truth is that the Czar Nicholas II
is physically weak, with shattered
nerves, and without much will of his
own. He is an amiable young man and
well-meaning: enough, but he is abso
lutely unfitted to be the autocratic
ruler of a country like Russia, where
an iron-handed administrator is essen
tial.
ET. PETERSBURG. Jan. 23.— One of
tbm permanent puzzles of the present
Cear's reign has been the remarkable
inconsistency with which Nicholas II
has conducted the Government of his
empire. AVhen he ascended the throne
he had the reputation of being a keen
reformer, yet he retained the most
reactionary of his father's Ministers in
cfSce. Since then he has alternated be
tween progressive and retrogressive
tendencies.
Czarina Pleadsfor
Liberality and
Progress.
Iron -Hand Policy
Suits Dowager
Empress.
BETWEEN FORCE OF A STRONG MOTHER AND CHARITY OF A DEVOTED
WIFE THE CZAR HALTS AND THE WORLD SAYS HE IS A WEAK MAN
SAN FRANCISCO, SUNDAY, JANUARY 24, 1904.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015679/1904-02-07/ed-1/?sp=35&q=Czar+little+nicholas&r=0.009,0.308,0.543,0.25,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Czar All in Russia is his
UNDREAMED OF LENGTHS to
which his subjects would go to carry
out his imperial will
HIS AUTOCRATIC POWER, fos
tered by the Church steadily increases
even in this democratic age
By WILLIAM THORP
A BUSY American hurried into the office of
the Russian Consul-General in New York
the other day to ask for some information
about Russia. As he stood by the wicket
Kate of the outer office, waiting for admission, the
Consul-General happened to notice him.
"Kindly remove your hat, sir," he said. "Do you
not see that you are standing in the presence of His
Majesty the Emperor of Russia?" and he pointed to
a colored portrait of the Czar on the wall.
In every Russian Legation and Consulate through
out the world there is or, at least, there ought to
be a similar portrait, and everybody who sees it is
obiiged to take off his hat and do reverence as if
he were in the actual presence of the ruler of all
the Russias. When such observances are exacted
in a bustling American -kyscraper, where scant rev
erence is paid to anybody or anything, it becomes
easier to understand the absolute, willing submission
of more than 90 per cent, of the Russian nation to
the will of one man.
Few American, although they talk glibly of the
despotism of the Czar, really comprehend the lengths
tf which that submission goes. Henry Norman, the
well-known English publicist, who is a leading au
thority op Russian affairs, told a striking story on
this head. He said that, during his recent travels in
Russia, he remarked to a Russian statesman that the
Trans Siberian Railroad would not realize the ex
pectation formed of it by the military party, be
cause it would be impossible to convey large masse
of troops, over the line to the Far Fast within a
short time.
WOULD ABANDON ALL
INTERNAL COMMERCE
IF NECESSARY
"And. pray, why would it be impossible?" asked
the statesman.
"There would not be enough rolling stock avail
able?" replied Mr. Norman.
"Rut every engine and carnage in Russia would
be put there if necessary."
"Surely that would not be possible." objected
the Fnglishman. "It would disorganize the entire
1 onimerce of the country, and bring ruin, and even
starvation, to tens of thousands of your people."
"I see you do not understand us yet," said the
Russian. "If the Czar gave the word to take every
railway carriage in Russia and run it across the
Siberian Railroad and throw it into the China Sea
at the other end. who. I would like to know, would
re vent it? Certainly, nobody in Russia would have
the audacious insolence and wickedness to attempt to
do so."
There M the real secret of the Czar's power over
his people. Disloyalty is. to the Russian, not only
a crime in the eyes of the law. but a heinous sin in
the eyes of God. The priests of the Orthodox
Church are never weary of driving that idea into the
heads of their flocks, but. indeed, they are preaching
to the converted. The average Russian in all grades
of society, but especially in the peasant class, is ab
solutely convinced of the Czar's divine right to
govern him and to dispose freely of his property, his
services, and even his life, exactly as he chooses. So
sacred is the person of the monarch. o utterly aloof
from other men. that even the head of the Church,
the chief minister of God. is not deemed competent
to crown him</text>
      </result>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1905-01-24/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Czar+Yacht&st=text&r=0.33,0.712,0.273,0.252,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CZAR'S STEAM YACHT IS READY FOR HIS ESCAPE
*::':^:>(v^Mfcg:!SK^'^^- 1-- -''^^^^^S^^j^^^y'- w"- 1'/ 1' ■!B^t^**^T^B^BK^^^^^^y^-'i:J^^^S^^^^Fiil^^B^Bfcj'^^^JS^**iii^ HK/^^S^ "^^Sl^^M^^^^^^-il^^-^^''^^ffl^f^wJ^^^ln^^flKtFi^^l!^^iifffllß^MKD^i'?^?SSMf'' i '"''l^^^r^ v I II
maw JF\, I IM. Hf^\
5:00 o'clock a. m.
FATHER GOPON IN~
HANDS OF POLICE
END OF ABSOLUTISM IN
RUSSIA IS NEAR
Famous Author Declares Sunday's
Slaughter Has Done What Years of
Propaganda Gould Not Accomplish
—People Now Regard the Czar
Their Enemy—Massacre Answered
by Dynamite—Moscow and Other
Large Cities Follow St. Petersburg
Cue, and Russia Will Be Forced to
Make Peace With Japan
Special Cable to The Globe
ST. PETERSBURG, Jan. 24, 11 a. m.—Father Gopon,
the leader of the Russian workmen,, has been arrested.
While speaking to a number of unarmed men in a side
street, a detail of secret service police, dressed as Rus
sian laborers, swooped down and before the workmen
realized what had happened, their leader was in the
hands, of the police. There was a frantic chase and the
news of the capture spread about almost instantaneous
ly. It was followed by three riots in different parts of
the city, in which no one was killed. The strikers have
obtained a large quantity of arms from some secret
source and a bloody outbreak is expected within a few
hours. There is a strange calmness in many parts of
the city that, is more trying to the authorities than actual
revolt. Hundreds of men are going quietly about the
city, defying the efforts of the secret police to fathom
their intentions. These are the agents of the revolu
tionary party and it looks as if a decisive blow was
about to be struck. Father Gopon's arrest will likely
hasten the outbreak, which will eclipse the horror of
Sunday's butchery.
(BY MAX/ME GORKY)
Special Cable to The Globe
ST. PETERSBURG, Jan. 23.—The Russian revolution has
begun. The bloody dawn of the day of freedom will be fol
lowed by more slaughter, but in the end the people will tri
umph. Sunday's 'awful proceedings have accomplished
what years of propaganda could not accomplish. Confidence
in the czar—the strongest article in the faith of the common
people of Russia —has been destroyed. This has been the in
surmountable breastwork behind which the aristocrats have
fought off every movement for reform in Russia. They have
shielded themselves behind the traditional love of the people
lor their supreme ruler.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-10-01/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Czar+home+Nicholas&r=-1.064,0,3.127,1.443,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>HOME LIFE OF THE CZAR
MOB TWO YEARS it was my duty to walk
hind Czar Nicholas II of Russia at a distance"
of five paces, following him not only when ho
JOKiX was in public place ill from room to room
mF^lj '"8 private apartment. In other words, 1
Jsj^rJ was his bodyguard, 111 man who was closer
to .him, physically, than any other individual
t^—^> in the Imperial service. I would inform
him .of the,, arrival of visitors, carry occasional
messages 0 for him, and jot down O notos of things
he desired to remember., I was usually on duty
for six hours each day; but sometimes it was necessary
for me to stay in the palace." for twelve hours on
end. I have seen the Czar in his joys and in his
sorrows; I have been present at his most intimate family
gatherings; and have stood at his elbow when he was
receiving his cabinet ministers, foreign diplomat! and
others. At times, too, I have been on duty in the private
apartment of the Czarina. Service of this nature led to
a relationship between the Imperial family and myself
that almost amounted to friendship. The Czar especi
ally gave me his entire confidence, chatting with mo
on any topic that inter
ested him at the moment;
and my knowledge of his
character, Of his tastes
and of his home life is,
therefore, authentic, and
Most of the time! I was
stationed at the Winter
Palais in St. Petersburg.
Piiflf/g the summer, the
Imperial household
stayed at Pcterhoff and
sometimes at the Tsar
skoe Belo palace. The
Czar occupied five rooms.</text>
      </result>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1912-07-07/ed-1/?sp=48&q=Czar+Nicholas</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Nicholas, tho present Czar of tho Russian
Empire, was a hoy or 12.
The Emperor was assassinated a Tow
hours befora tlio rime when he was ex
pected to givo hU Hanctlon to a proclama
tion which win to grant to tho Russian
people a semblance of a constitutional
form of government. Tho assassination
of tho Czar filled the reactionaries with
new hope, and through the efforts of
Pobycdonodtscff and others tho proclama
tion which tho new Czar was ready to
sign was not Issued. Pobyedonodtseff
delivered a Hpeech in tho Council of tho
empire, which was a tnastorpieco of ora
torical hypocrisy and falsehood, and the
words or tho clever, unprincipled and
dishonest bureaucrat persuaded the new
Emperor, who was not inclined to a con
stitutional form of government.
Nicholas was at that time a weak boy of
U too young to understand fully what
was going on about him. But the first
strong Impressions of his youth were
these bloody pages of Russian history.
But at that time no one paid much at
tention to the fate of the boy In the plain
sailor suit with the thin neck and pretty
eyes which ho had 'inherited from his
mother.
As for the Czar himself he was appar
ently dissatiflsed with his rdle at the
centre of tho Government. Even St.
Petersburg itself was disagreeable to
blm because of the recollections asso
ciated with It: he was afraid of IU broad
prospects and squares where the annoying
revolutionists were so often conspiring
agairust tho life of the Czars. The Russian
court was removed to Gatohlna.
Since the days of Paul I., Oatohlna has
borne the stamp of barracks, All is gray
and dull there.
The family virtues of Alexander har
monized splendidly with his modest mode
of life. The childhood years of Nicholas
and of bis brothers passed amid sur
roundings from which the love Intrigues
characteristic of the Russian court were
absent. There the children could get a
proper education, but Alexander, who
had received only a meagre education
himself, who was weakened by aloohollsm I
and by his earlier mode of life, did not
concern himself with the education of the
Crown Prince.
Mr. Heath, an Englishman, called In
Russia Karl Onlpovlch, was the tutor
of Nicholas and his brothers. Aa Idealist,
well educated, a splendid artist and a
sportsman, Mr. Heath brought with him
to the palace his great devotion to tho
Czar's family. Rut neither the forty years
he bad spent in Russia nor his meetings
and discussions with Russians gave him
any real knowledge of the Russian land,
toe ttusslan eoplo or K nlstory. lliore-
foro his influence was llroltod only to
the walls of the nurmry
In curly childhood tho influence, of the
English tulor timiilfested iteolf In the fact
that t!u KiirIIi-Ii litiiKiiago altnnht crowded
out the Kuvxlau l.uiKUUKe at the Impvriul
court. And even many year later, when
Nichols hud Ux'tiii'" i'ar, hi KiiHtian
speeches, when not prepared for him by
some one else, were literal translations of
Kagllch phrases.
I
In his childhood day the first place
was given to sports of nil kinds. Nicholas
was good at jumping, shooting and fish-</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1917-03-18/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Czar+Dethroned+Nicholas</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1905-11-01/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Czar+Concessions+Nicholas+Russia</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>To ascertain tho precise purport oitho
tho concessions made by NICHOLAS I
to his peoples demand for representative
ire institutions we should disregardheadlines
headlines nnd all unofficial interpretations
tions and fix our eyes on the exact wordof
of tho imperial manifesto and of theonly
only trustworthy commentary namelyCount
Count WITTES report on which theCzar
Czar with his own hands Inscribed thewords
words To bo taken for guide As wehave
have both of these documents wo canconstruo
construo them for ourselvesLet
Let us begin by noting what wo donot
not find in tho manifesto Tho Czardoes
does not grant to his subjects what InEnglish
English speaking countries wo are accustomed
tomed to regard as the palladium ofindividual
individual liberty that Is to say hedoes
does not authorize the courts t Issue awrit
writ of habeas corpus That is the onoefficient
efficient method of assuring in practicetho
tho inviolability of person which thoCzar
Czar vaguely promises and orders hisGovernment
Government to assure Without thowrit
writ of habeas corpus that promise canbo
be easily evaded as it is evaded dollyIn
secondplace
In tho French republic In the
place the manifesto does not empowertho
the national assembly about to be electedto
to frame a constitution which amongother
other fundamental things should definetho
tho relation of tho Czar t tho Govorment
ment including for example tho exercise
cio of the veto power It does notauthorize
authorize the assembly to decide howtho
tho army and navy shall be controlledIt
I does not in so many words accepttho
tho principle of Ministerial accountabilityto
t the peoples representatives It doesnot
not assert the principle of universalsuffrage
suffrage or oven define how close anapproach
approach shall be mao to it a thobasis
basis of tho State Duma or nationalassembly
assembly now on tho eve of beingchosen
chosen but merely invites those classesof
of tho population now completely deprived
prived of the franchise tho classeswhich
prve cnleswhch
which have brought about tho existngstiketo
strike to participate in tho comingelection
election so far a tho limited timobeforo
before the convocation of the assemblyshall
shall permit That is the Ministers aroto
to decide as to any given city whetherand
and how far tho present restrictions ontho
the suffrage may b modifiedSo
So much for tho omissions reservations
tions and ambiguities in tho text of thoCzars
Czars manifesto Lot us say franklythat
that they aro fewer than might havebeen
been expected Tho positive concessions
sions made are broad and solid In thohands
hands of well meaning and resoluteMinisters
Ministers they may bo made to sere astho
the foundations of 0 superstructuresatisfactory
satisfactory to the advocates of constitutional
satRfactorr const
tutional government By granting tohis
his people the primary civil rightsfreedom
freedom of conscience freedom ofspeech
speech which of course includes freedom
dom of tho press and freedom of association
elation which a obviously includes thoright
right to hold meetings private or public
Ictho Czar has unchained the imponderable
ponderable but almost irresistible forcoknown
known as public opinion which so farns
ns Russias urban population is concerned
corned is likely to guide the exerciseof</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1921-11-06/ed-1/?sp=24&q=Czar+Nicholas&r=-0.954,-0.029,2.909,1.343,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>IE CZAR.
ILL-FATED I

-Tatiana and Olga, daughtt
are believed to have met d
while prisoners at Ekaterinbu
in the Empress. Why should they
treat the Tsar so? He, who loved
Russia with his whole soul.
MONDAY. APRIL, 9.-Kerensky
intended to isolate the Empress, but
he was told that it would be utterly
inhuman to separate a mother from
,ier four sick children. Then he de
termined to isolate the Tsar.
Taken to Tobolsk.
On August 12 we learned that the
family and those who chose to ac
company it were to be taken to
Tobolsk, Siberia. The next day,
under a heavy guard of armed cav
alry, we were taken to the station
and began our long journey. Ahead
of us-bleak and unhospitable
Siberia. What a terrible fall for a
family so whole-heartedly devoted to
Russia!
At first our exile at Tobolsk, al
though we were always kept strict
prisoners, was not very trying.
On November 15 we heard that the
provisional government had been
overthrown.
Kerenaky fled. The Bolsheviks
obtained control. This was immedi
ately reflected in our treatment.
The soldierA, who up to this time
had treated us fairly well, became
giore and more insolent, delighting
in doing everything to show the
royal family their degradation.
They naAe them undergo every
privation and heaped them with in
suits of the most brutal and beastly
character. This spirit is shown by
an entry in my diary for January,
1D17.
Wednesday. January 14.-A com
mittee of soldiers of our garrison
decided by 100 votes to S. that epau
lettes should be taken from officers
and soldiers.
When he heard of the ignomini
ous Brest-Litovsk treatv the Czar
w'as dumbfounded. 1Itussi-a was
ruined. In this treaty the Ger
mansI1 demandedl thait the Russian
imperial family be handed over to
them safe and sound.
It is a shame." said the Czar.
it means suicidle for- flussia. I
would never have thought that the
G;erman Emperor and the German
governmen t (-ould lower- itself to
shake hands with these miserable
men who have betrayed their counl
try."
WVhen the Czarina lea rned of the
terms of the treaty she said (quielly:
"After what they have done to the
Czar I would rather die In Russia
thtan be saved by Germany."
"I would rather cut of f my right
hand than sign this treaty," said the
C'zar. Aend from that time on lie
became terribly depressed.
Thursday. April 25.-G;od help uis'
It is coming. The beginning of the
en~d is approaching.
At 3 O'clock that afternoon I met
two of the Czar's most faithful sor'
ants, who broke out with sobs when
thley saw mec. "'Th'y have comew
eamue-t o take awa y our master.
afte ai I daiy o'f sor-row andl ani
guish, the servants ;81Enm to the
hail to bid t heir Majestiles good-by.
The Thiporer- and his wife were
tobe se'parIateId from the (chidren
whomt they loved more thant the
whole world.
SThe End Approaches.
Finnly~ at 3 o'clock in the morn
ing I heard a rumbling, and looking
01m or thb windows saw peasant
earls outside the house. These earts
were only fit to carry flour sacks
aund livestock. Whait ?-wers they 4
goIng to take away the ('zar and 1
The wagons We-ro filthy and we i
triedl to elonn thm. ...tho.u.. .m.ch
tIBES SL
AND HIS
DRINCESSE
rs of Czar Nicholas II, who
sath at hands of Bolsheviki
rg.
success. We found a little straw in
a pig sty with which we covered the
floor of the oart.
Then we went upstairs. Their Ma.
jesties were kneeling beside the. bed
of the little prince-he who was sub
ject to such a terrible malady that
they felt they would never see him
alive again. The Czarina took Alex.
is' head in her arms and kissel
him again and again. Then, sud
denly, she kissed him for the last
time and turning brusquely.
walked out of the room, not daring;
to look back. Her eyes were bri t
ming with tears.
We came downstairs. Outside the
soldiers were stamping and grum
bling impatiently. They had no pity
for the tragedy which was being en
acted in the house. What did it
mean to them that a loving family
was broken up under conditions ao
terrible?
After a sad farewell, everyone
was strangled with grief. We beard
the wagons rumbling away. We
were alone-the children and I
with a few faithful servants.
We heard after three weeks of ag
ony, that their Majesties were im
prisoned in a merchant's house at
Ekaterinburg under a most brutal
red guard.
On Monday, May 20, we left To
bolsk under a strong guard. We
heard that we were going to rejoin
the Czar and Czarina. But we fear
ed that that was only a cruel joke on
the part of the Bolsheviks.
I feared that the worst was go
ing to happen. It was pitiful under
such conditions to see the children.]
faces lighten up as the boat drew
near Tioumen, where we were to
take a train for Ekaterinburg. They
longed to see their mother and .a
ther once again.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
